We will see the importance of the influence of this fold,
this flexion of the embryo,
at the upper part of the intestine.
The embryo makes a flexion movement.
Now, if I take this image,
and I rewind it.
I do it like this here.
I rewind, I do this.
Through the covering of the embryo,
the mesenchyme, this mesenchymal tissue,
sub-mesencephalic,
perpendicular to the longitudinal axis, we see that it makes this
movement that gives this nice curvature, this orientation will
create a
compression here between the front and the back, forming the
base of the skull, which is
a dynamic movement. There is a field here; it creates a cartilaginous field at
first, it has a bit of an axe, and then through this movement, it
creates
primitive, compressed cartilages.
Its expression will be a strong release of energy.
Here, I have the amniotic cavity, the yolk sac.
Now, I take just the yellow here,
and I take the yolk sac with the endoderm above.
Now, we are in this movement of embryo development
where it makes this flexion movement.
So, I have my yolk sac.
Here, okay, the yolk sac is there, then it will find itself
there, my neural tube which
comes to wrap, initially I have the cardiac area which is quite forward. The movement
of the embryo's flexion, we will study it from the periphery to
the inside,
so from the visible face, we can touch in the mouth up
to the level of the
pharyngeal intestine. This flexion movement,
organizes this particularity of my face, from the periphery, toward
the inside.
It’s my notochord that induces my neural tube, which induces my
arteries,
and it’s the wrapping around my arterial system that comes to be organized.
So initially, schematically, I notice that the upper part
of my intestine
is a joint that occurs.
Between my heart and my brain.
I now have this small
thing appearing, the foregut, here,
which appears, the upper intestine
that is forming,
here. It’s a joint
between the heart
and the brain
that develops here, you see, there.
Oriented, organized in space-time
by the amniotic fluid,
but whose point of support
is the vascular
system. This is my...
yolk sac. There is the heart right here,
which we see very high up, we see it here,
and we see
the wrapping here, you see,
and we see that it’s a joint
between the heart
and the developing brain.
It will delimit the space
of the part
of my yolk sac in its
anterior part to form
this small loop here.
The more it continues, the more it will organize.
Here I have the large yolk sac, and finally, I have the remnant of this yolk sac right here.
And so I see that this upper part here will organize within these flexion movements.
Amniotic cavity, we see the heart, and you see, look here, the space that will be created.
It’s a joint between the heart and the brain, driven by the
amniotic growth.
And there I have the beginning of the formation.
Formation of my digestive tube that organizes along a longitudinal plane.
It’s the delimitation here that is being made.
It’s the whole organization of my digestive tube that starts to take place.
Formation of the upper part of my intestine.
Integration of the allantois, the cloacal membrane that will form here.
And between this membrane here, this will be formed.
To develop the pharyngeal membrane, thus the rudiment at
the buccal level. We can see well,
look closely, how it is a joint between the brain, the
amniotic sac, the heart
as the support point, organized by the differential growth rate
of my
vascular system. It’s a balance between my brain and my heart.
Guided by my mesoderm, by the fluidic aspect of my mesoderm,
or in other words, by the vascular aspect of my mesoderm.
The emergence of a vessel always depends on various components.
A field, a metabolic concentration, a trajectory, vacuolations
and the presence of interstitial particles.
It’s a component that appears and disappears.
That’s why in your embryo, you can have vessels that come
and with time, you have vessels that disappear. That’s why it comes from the periphery towards
the center. Pages and two vessels, two large aortas, and then they come to center
into one aorta. The influence of this folding will organize the internal delimitation
of the upper
digestive tube. We will now go into details.